

Santiago BARROSO Software engineer

★ Madrid (Spain)

+34 688 91 05 57

SUMMARY

Software developer with more than 15 years of experience.

I studied computer science in Madrid, obtaining a degree in 2003. I spent my first years working with PHP, C and Shell script technologies; after that I specialized in Java technologies (J2EE, GWT, Spring, Hibernate, ...) and since 2015 I have been mainly focused in Javascript and the various frameworks around it: Angular2, React, Node, etc.

I feel confident in both backend and frontend and I am passionate about new technologies and keen on taking new challenges with every new role. I have worked in Spain, France, England and Gibraltar and that international experience, besides my language and interpersonal skills, speaking fluently spanish, french and english has made me progress in my career.

EXPERIENCE

Nov 2016 - Gamelearn, Madrid

Senior Javascript developer

Development of management platform, both back-end (Node, MongoDB, Redis, AWS, Docker) and front-end (Angular5): CRUD operations and much more using a REST API

Development of game-based learning applications (ReactJs, Redux).

I am involved in all the development stages from analysis of the requirements to the implementation and tests of the solution

Technology: NodeJs, MongoDb, Redis, Mandrill, Docker, Nginx, Angular4, ReactJs, Amazon Web Services

Nov 2015 - Nov 2016

Sopra, Madrid

Senior Java developer

Working in a project for the Societe generale bank. Analysis and development of solutions to improve the quality of web applications.

Technology: Java, JQuery, Maven, Spring

Oct 2014 - Oct 2015

Odobo, Gibraltar

Engine developer

I was in charge of developing the server-side logic of different casino games, including Slots, card games, scratch games and others. Also involved in developing some of the front end applications using Javascript technologies.

Technology: Java, NodeJs, Guice, Maven, JQuery, MongoDB, JAXB.

Aug 2013 - Jun 2014

First Clarity, London

Senior Java developer

Development and maintenance of publishing sites: Irish Independent and Belfast Telegraph. I was involved in both the back (Java, Spring, Rest) and the front end using (Jsp, Jstl, JQuery).

Technology: Java, Spring, Maven, Jquery, Rest.

Oct 2012 - Jul 2013

Mfuse, London

Senior Java developer

I was involved in the maintenance of the Ladbrokes' mobile web site and in the development of MyBet's. Most of the work was in the front end using technologies as GWT, HTML, CSS and javascript. Development of gambling games to use in mobile environments.

Technology: Java, GWT, Spring, Hazelcast, CSS, Javascript, PlayN, LibGDX.

Dec 2010 - Jul 2012

Normasys, Paris

Senior Java/GWT developer

Development of an electronic shelf labelling solution for the retail industries. I was involved in nearly all the stages of the project, analysing requirements with the client, designing the best solution and developing both the client and the server sides. The application was build with GWT (front end) and Hibernate/JPA/MySQL (back end)

Technology: Java, Spring(Core, Transaction, Security, Task), Maven, GWT (Smartgwt et Gwt native), Hibernate, JPA, Web Services Rest, JAXB, JNDI, IzPack, CSS, Archiva, JIRA, Confluence, Jenkins, Checkstyle, PMD.

Dec 2007 - Dec 2010

Tragsa, Madrid

Senior Java developer

Client 1: Ministry of environment.

Development of a site that will hold the catalogue of the national cattle to be used by both public employees and the general public. I was involved in both the front end (Spring Webflow, Spring MVC, reports in Excel/Word using the Apache POI API ,etc) and the back end (Hibernate/Spring, Oraclet) The web of the project can be seen at

http://aplicaciones.magrama.es/arca-webapp

Technology: Java, Spring (Core, MVC, WebFlow, Transaction, Security), Maven, Artifactory, JSP, Hibernate, JPA, JAXB, Apache POI, Selenium, DBUnit, Velocity.

Client 2: Ministry of Justice.

Development of an application to make the digital scanning of all proceedings in the ministry. Front end was built using Spring Webflow, MVC, Javascript, JQuery, CSS, Tiles Back end used Hibernate/JPA/Oracle and web services were developed using the Apache CXF framework (SOAP and Rest services) Contributing to the design of all parts of the application, notably in the web services, JAXB, Hibernate and web flow ones.

Technology: Java, Spring (Core, MVC, WebFlow, Transaction, Security), Maven, Artifactory, JSP, Hibernate, JPA, JAXB, Apache POI, Selenium, DBUnit, Velocity.

Mar 2006 - Dec 2007

Net2S, Madrid

Software analyst

Client 1: Telefonica I+D.

Development of a web application to manage Cisco routers.

Technology: Java, Servlets, Jsp, Struts, Cisco technology.

21/9/2018 CV Santiago Barroso

Client 2: Vodafone.

Maintenance of the database. Development of scripts to fix bugs in the database.

Technology: Scripts, Sql Server, SQL, PL-SQL.

Nov 2004 - Mar 2006

Aplica, Madrid

Developer

Development of a surveillance platform enabling user to configure sensors that will trigger recordings of the webcams. Development of the web application, the mobile WAP site and the drivers to communicate with the differents servers and webcams used. I was deeply involved in all phases of the project: analysis, design, development, tests and support to the clients.

Technology: PHP, C, Java (Applets), Scripts Linux, WAP.

Jul 2003 - Nov 2004

Coritel, Madrid

Developer

Working for the evolutive maintenance project in the client company Vodafone, fix bugs and improvement of the applications. Develop scripts for database maintenance.

Technology: C, Scripts Unix, Bat files, SQL, PL-SQL.

Dec 2002 - May 2003

Digibis, Madrid

Internship

Development of an LDAP system for the company and tests for other applications.

Technology: ASP, Access, Excel, Visual Basic.

EDUCATION

1998 - 2003 Universidad Autónoma de Madrid (UAM), Madrid

Degree in computer science

2010 Certification SCWCD (Sun Certified Web Component Developer)

2008 Certification SCJP (Sun Certified Java Programmer 5.0)

2007 Certification CCNA (CISCO)

1995 - 2000 Language Official School, Madrid, English Certification B2

2006 - 2010 Language Official School, Madrid, French Certification B2

1998 Driving license

1996 Typing certification

SKILLS

Software Knowledge

Javascript

Angular

ReactJS

Java

Spring Maven Hibernate

GWT JAXB

XML

JPA

Shell script

CSS

Software tools • Jenkins

Travis

Docker

Ansible

Languages • Spanish: native

English: fluentFrench: fluentwriting/reading/spokewriting/reading/spoken

Go to Top